# **Professional Profile**

Data analytics leader, currently pursuing a Master of Information and Data Science degree at the University of California, Berkeley. 20 years of experience in a wide variety of roles and industries including healthcare, financial services, management consulting, and mining, using data to solve business problems.

## **Education**

University of California, Berkeley – Master of Information and Data Science

2019 (anticipated)

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign – Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

1999

Co-founder, University of Illinois Society of Business and Management in Engineering

#### **Skills and Tools**

#### **Key Technical Skills**

- Tools: Python, Spark, Hadoop MapReduce, SQL, R, Tableau, TensorFlow (including GPU deep learning)
- Machine Learning at Scale
- Data Wrangling / Feature Engineering
- Natural Language Processing

#### **Key Business Skills**

- Team Leadership
- Lean Six Sigma Black Belt
- Project Management
- Financial Modeling
- Executive Communication

## **Experience**

#### Data Science Student, University of California, Berkeley

2017 - 2019

- Predicted Russian misinformation campaign tweets in the 2016 election with 99% accuracy using natural language processing and a TensorFlow based LSTM neural network using both tweet text and metadata.
- Determined customer churn likelihood and financial impact for a music subscription service with 97% accuracy using an XGBoost model.
- Predicted likelihood of violent crimes in the City of Denver using multiple machine learning models to evaluate over 10 million data points of locations and crimes by date.
- Estimated future sales of a German retailer at 1,100 stores using an XGBoost model.
- Predicted employee flight risk of 15,000 employee workforce using multiple machine learning models.

#### **Speaker and Thought Leader, Talent Analytics**

2015 - 2017

- Presented leading practices for building HR Analytics teams and infrastructure at industry conferences
  through the Society for Industrial and Organizational Psychology (SIOP), the Talent Management Alliance
  (TMA), the International Quality & Productivity Center (IQPC), and the Best Practice Institute (BPI).
- Rated best workshop at the 2017 SIOP annual conference.
- Designed and developed a simulated 12,000 employee company using R and Tableau. Used simulation to deliver a workshop to train participants in reporting and analytics techniques.

DaVita, Inc. 2011 – 2015

Director, HR Analytics

- Founded and led DaVita's HR Analytics function. Led team to produce numerous in-depth studies along with over 200 regular and ad hoc reports monthly, involving millions of records of over 100,000 employees, past and present.
- Statistically quantified which HR variables most impacted patient clinical outcomes and business value. Distilled 250,000 results down to 14 meaningful findings (results confidential).

# Cameron Kennedy

- Reduced early turnover by 51% by quantifying the impact of pre-employment assessments.
- Increased team time spent on priority projects by 88% by establishing project management practices.
- Reduced reporting time of employee turnover and promotions from 3 weeks to 1 day.
- Established business intelligence capability (Tableau) for visualizing and analyzing data.
- Solved frequent data integrity issues by instituting data governance and source data audits.
- Overhauled defective central HR data repository. Migrated from multiple Microsoft Access and other databases to a single SQL Server instance.

Director, Strategy and Special Projects, Office of the Chief People Officer

- Served as Chief of Staff to the Chief People Officer in support of DaVita's ~50,000 employees.
- Developed and delivered numerous presentations to executive stakeholders.
- Mitigated executive flight risk and established executive compensation packages for the due diligence of DaVita's \$4.4 billion acquisition of HealthCare Partners.
- Prevented over \$15 million in overspend by fixing wage analysis for 7,000 annual hires.
- Aligned executive compensation with business unit performance by overhauling DaVita's long-term incentive plan (LTIP) compensation, changing from an equity-only to a cash and equity mix.
- Formed DaVita Village Trust nonprofit organization and merged two existing nonprofits into it.

#### **Newmont Mining Corporation**

2007 - 2011

Senior Manager, Capital Investment and Analysis

- Managed Newmont's \$2 billion annual capital budget.
- Controlled excessive spending and improved investment decision making by overhauling the authorization for expenditure processes, developing a large-project decision framework, and building or reviewing hundreds of financial models.
- Directed Regional Capital Managers in the United States, Peru, Australia, Indonesia, and Ghana.
- Developed and deployed standardized financial models to evaluate projects with common return metrics.

Global Finance Lead and Lean Six Sigma Black Belt, Business Excellence

- Led the formation and execution of the global finance function for Newmont's Lean Six Sigma program.
- Saved \$5 million annually leading a Lean Six Sigma project in the corporate supply chain function.
- Built executive leadership confidence in the Lean Six Sigma program by quantifying \$99 million in five-year value and a 97% internal rate of return.
- Improved overall company financial acumen by training Newmont's Black Belts in financial modeling.

# Arthur Andersen (Business Consulting Division) / KPMG Consulting

1999 – 2006

Manager in the Business Strategy / Growth Solutions Practice

- Led numerous financial analyses for large global companies, highlighting uncontrolled spend, providing total cost of ownership, and identifying opportunities to improve financial alignment to the business.
- Led the financial analysis and quantitative customer needs portions of an engagement that developed a strategy to increase the commercial deposit assets of a top 20 US bank from \$5 billion to \$15 billion.
- Managed a pilot sales force organizational overhaul of a large insurance industry client.

## **Volunteer and Other Notable Experience**

- Challenge Aspen, Snowmass Village, CO: Board of Directors (December 2015 Present).
- **George Washington University**, Washington, DC: Financial analytics tutor to undergraduate economics student.
- University of Denver, Denver, CO: Business advisor to Masters in Business Analytics student.